Guide to the Louis J. Budd Papers, 1928-2006
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Louis J. Budd papers 1928-2006
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Budd, Louis J.
1.5 linear feet Extent: Approximately 900 Items
Duke University Professor of English and Fulbright-Hayes lecturer at the American Studies Research Centre, Hyderabad, India. Collection contains correspondence, printed material, and materials relating to the journal publishing process. There are also a few journals, notes, and writing drafts. The correspondence pertains chiefly to the Jay B. Hubbell Center for Literary Historiography at Duke University, with many letters written by Budd for the purpose of fundraising, acquiring scholars' papers for the Center, and thanking individuals for their contributions and support. Other correspondence relates to the Modern Language Association, its American Literature Section, the Norman Foerster Award, the formation and activities of MLA's divisions, and the place of American literature in India. Acquired as part of the Jay B. Hubbell Center for American Literary Historiography at Duke University.
buddlouis
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Louis J. Budd Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 1977, 2008 and 2011.
Biographical Note
Louis J. Budd was a Duke University Professor of English and Fulbright-Hayes lecturer at the American Studies Research Centre, Hyderabad, India.
Collection Overview
Collection contains correspondence, printed material, and materials relating to the journal publishing process. There are also a few journals, notes, audio cassettes, and writing drafts. The correspondence pertains chiefly to the Jay B. Hubbell Center for Literary Historiography at Duke University, with many letters written by Budd for the purpose of fundraising, acquiring scholars' papers for the Center, and thanking individuals for their contributions and support. Other correspondence relates to the Modern Language Association, its American Literature Section, the Norman Foerster Award, and the formation and activities of MLA's divisions. There is also correspondence by Louis Budd to scholars, asking for reminiscences about early teachers of American literature, and exchanges with Willard Thorpe. Print material includes articles by Budd and other scholars, clippings, and an article entitled Reminiscences of Jay B. Hubbell by Clarence Gohdes. Other printed material relates to the American Research Studies Center in India, and the place of American literature in the studies in India. A small group of papers regards Professor Budd's guest editorship of the Vol. 2, No. 3, Jan. 1976 issue of Studies in American Humor. Other papers include materials on the early days of the Melville Society and meeting minutes on an edition of Washington Irving writings.
Acquired as part of the Jay B. Hubbell Center for American Literary Historiography at Duke University.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Budd, Louis J.; Hubbell, Jay B. (Jay Broadus), 1885-1979; American Research Studies Centre (India)--History; Duke University. Department of English; Jay B. Hubbell Center for American Literary Historiography (Duke University); Modern Language Association. American Literature Section; American literature -- Study and teaching; Audiocassettes
Related Material
Jay B. Hubbell Papers, 1816-2003 and undated, bulk 1920-1979
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Contents of Collection
- Audio Series, 1976-1981, (1 folder)
  Two audio cassettes from Jack Rosenbalm (?), one by Jack Meathenia of Studies in American Humor and another unidentified cassette. Both are accompanied by letters addressed to Budd regarding the cassettes' general contents.
  - Audiocassettes, undated, (2 cassettes) (Box 1)
- Correspondence Series, 1928-2006, (16 folders)
  Contains both fundraising and general correspondence to and from Budd regarding the Hubbell Center. Correspondence often refers to acquiring literary scholars' papers for the Center, as well as letters thanking individuals for contributions and their attempts to increase awareness of the Hubbell Center and its goals. Some correspondence regarding Budd's work with the Hubbell Medallion Committee, as well as his work judging for the Ritz Paris Hemingway Award and the Norman Foerster Award. Correspondence related to a special issue of Studies in American Humor edited by Budd. Other correspondence deals with various authors in the field of American literature and other literary topics.
  - Awards, 1977-1985, (2 folders)
    - Norman Foerster Award, 1977 (Box 1)
    - Ritz Paris Hemingway Award, 1984-1985 (Box 1)
  - Hubbell Center, 1972-1987
    - Fund raising for Hubbell Center, 1976-1979 (Box 1)
    - Hubbell Center correspondence, 1975-1987; (5 folders) (Box 1)
    - Jay B. Hubbell Medal, 1972-1981 (Box 1)
  - Other Correspondence, 1976-1987
    - Committee on Manuscript Holdings, 1971 (Box 1)
    - Correspondence, 1981-1991 (Box 1)
    - Correspondence and other items, 1980-2006 and undated (Box 1)
    - Memorials, clippings, and correspondence, 1928-1986 (Box 1)
    - MLA Divisions, 1974-1979 (Box 1)
    - NCVCEA, 1977-1978 (Box 1)
    - Special issue of Studies in American Humor: Mark Twain in the 1870s, 1975-1976 (Box 2)
- Other Writings Series, 1976-1987, (12 folders)
  Collection of papers and articles on American literature. Includes drafts and copies of special edition of Studies in American Humor edited by Budd, and papers relating to the American Studies Research Centre in India.
  - Fulbright/American Studies Research Centre, 1972-1976; (4 folders) (Box 2)
  - Irving Edition meeting minutes, 1966-1970 (Box 2)
  - Special issue of Studies in American Humor: "Mark Twain in the 1870s,", 1976 (Box 2)
  - Writings by others, 1972-1976; (6 folders)
    Chiefly articles on American literature by authors other than Louis Budd, materials regarding the Hubbell Center at Duke University, and reminiscences on Jay B. Hubbell and on the teaching of American literature.
    - Printed materials, 1970-1985 and undated; (4 folders) (Box 3)
    - Reminiscences, 1976-1984 (Box 3)